http://www.illinoislottery.com/policy/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
$1 MILLION ON ROUTE 66!
TURN MILES INTO
ENTER 2ND CHANCE PROMOTION
Skip the forthcoming terms and conditions navigation
INTRODUCTION
INFORMATION AUTOMATICALLY COLLECTED WHEN YOU VISIT THIS WEBSITE
USE OUTSIDE OF THE UNITED STATES
WEBSITE FOR ADULT USE ONLY (AGE 18 AND OLDER)
Help Center
Do you have any questions these T&C? Call us at 1-800-252-1775 or email us at support@illionoislottery.com
CONTACT US
Privacy Policy
Illinois Lottery Privacy Notice
Effective July 1, 2020.
INTRODUCTION
Thank you for visiting the Illinois Lottery’s website, which includes www.illinoislottery.com,  www.myillinoislottery.com, and https://m.myillinoislottery.com (collectively, the "Lottery Websites") or the Illinois Lottery's ticket purchase mobile app ("Mobile App") for any purpose (the Mobile App and the Lottery Websites collectively, the "Websites" or the "Website"). The Website Providers (defined below) recognize that you need to understand how your privacy is protected when you visit this Website. As such, the Website Providers have established this Privacy Notice. For purposes of this Privacy Notice, the "Website Providers" means the Illinois Department of the Lottery, including its agents, contractors, and any parties involved in creating, producing, or delivering the Websites or providing information related to the Websites, including, but not limited to, Camelot Illinois LLC ("Camelot Illinois") and each of their respective successors and assigns.
This Privacy Notice is subject to change at any time without notice to you by posting changes on a Website. The Website Providers encourage you to review this Privacy Notice from time to time. Your continued use of any Website following any changes made to this Privacy Notice will mean that you accept the revised Privacy Notice.
This Privacy Notice describes the Illinois Lottery's privacy practices regarding information collected from you when you visit the Websites. This Privacy Notice describes what information is collected and how that information is used. Because this Privacy Notice only applies to the Websites, if you link to another entity’s website or mobile app through a Website, you should examine that entity’s privacy notice to determine its website practices (including other state agency websites).
For purposes of this Privacy Notice, "you" or "your" means each person, group of individuals, entity or entities who visits a Website for any purpose.
For purposes of this Privacy Notice, Personally Identifiable Information ("PII") means information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. PII includes, among other information, an individual's name, address, telephone number, date of birth, password information, and any other information used to identify you on this Website. A domain name or Internet protocol address is not considered PII. PII does not include publicly available information that is lawfully made available to the general public from federal, state, or local government records.
You must be 18 years or older to use the Websites. If you attempt to purchase Illinois Lottery game tickets for Lotto, Mega Millions®, Powerball®, or any other Illinois Lottery games authorized by law to be sold via the internet ("Internet Tickets") or a subscription for specific Illinois Lottery games ("Lottery Subscription") by visiting www.illinoislottery.com,  www.myillinoislottery.com or www.m.myillinoislottery.com, the Website Providers will collect information about your Internet protocol ("IP") address via geo-filtering software. If you attempt to purchase Internet Tickets using your mobile device, precise information about your location such as longitude, latitude and radius will also be collected by the Mobile Device Geo-Location Service (Device Geo-location Service). You must check the box authorizing the Device Geo-location Service to collect precise geo-location data about your device if you want to purchase Internet Tickets. Note that you will not be authorized to purchase Internet Tickets from your mobile device if you do not authorize the collection of precise geo-location data about you.
INFORMATION AUTOMATICALLY COLLECTED WHEN YOU VISIT THIS WEBSITE
A.   Information Collected
If you visit a Website and do nothing further, including, but not limited to, browsing, viewing rules or winning numbers, the Website Providers, will automatically gather and store the information about your visit, including, but not limited to, the following:
1. the Internet protocol ("IP") address and domain name used (for example, aol.com if you are accessing from AOL). The IP address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet Service Provider (“ISP”) or directly to your computer. Your location may also be identified via geo-filtering of your IP address;
2. the type of browser and operating system you used;
3. the date and time you visited the Website;
4. the web pages or services you accessed at the Website;
5. the website you visited prior to coming to the Website;
6. the website you visit as you leave the Website;
7. any ads you clicked on to access the Website;
8. if you use the ShareThis feature, what content you share from the Website, with whom you share the content, and where you post the content;
9. if you downloaded a form or other document, the form or document that was downloaded; and
10. the name of the country in which your server is located.
None of the foregoing information is deemed to be PII.
The foregoing information is used by the Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers (defined below) to improve the Website's content, understand how you interact with the Website, and deliver online marketing (but not marketing emails, unless you opt-in). This information is also collected for statistical analysis to determine what information is of most and least interest to you, to improve the utility of the material available on the Website, and for other purposes described in this Privacy Notice. Methods through which your information may be automatically collected include, but are not limited to cookies and banner ads.
B.   Cookies
Cookies are text files stored on your web browser to provide a means of distinguishing you from other visitors to a Website. To better serve you, the Website Providers use “transactional cookies” to enhance or customize your visit to a Website and to recognize you when you visit again. The software and hardware you use to access a Website may allow you to refuse new cookies or delete existing cookies. Refusing or deleting these cookies may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of a Website.
C.   Banner Ads
Banner ads will be used to advertise Illinois Lottery products.  The Websites will track the number of clicks on such ads for analytical and marketing purposes.
PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED
In addition to the information automatically collected in Section II above, information including, but not limited to the following, may also be collected:
A.   Emails, Surveys, & Electronic Newsletter Subscriptions
If you participate in a survey, send an email, or subscribe to an electronic newsletter, this Website will gather the following information, some of which may be considered PII:
1. the email address and contents of the email;
2. information volunteered in response to a survey; and
3. any information required by or volunteered on the electronic newsletter subscription form.
B.   Social Media and RSS Feeds
If you "like," follow, or otherwise contact the Illinois Lottery via social media (e.g., Facebook or Twitter), or subscribe to the Illinois Lottery via RSS feed, the Websites will collect the following information:
1. the social media username you used (e.g., Facebook or Twitter username)
2. the number of "likes;"" and
3. the total number of subscribers to our RSS feeds (but will not track where they posted the feeds)
C.   Player Account
If you sign up for a Players Account, which is required to purchase Internet Tickets or a Lottery Subscription, the Websites will collect information, including, but not limited to. the following:
i.  Mandatory Registration Personal Information
The following Personal Information will be collected at initial registration and is necessary for the creation and administration of a Players Account.  This information will be stored by the Website Providers and/or certain third parties in a contractual relationship with the Website Providers (“Third Party Service Providers”) and with each other:
1. name (first, last);
2. whether you are an individual or a business;
3. email address;
4. username (self-selected);
5. password (self-selected);
6. password hints and security questions;
7. (postal) mailing address;
8. (postal) billing address;
9. whether or not you are a resident of Illinois;
10. whether or not you are a United States non-resident alien;
11. social security number;
12. date of birth; and
13. phone number.
ii.   Mandatory Personal Information for Funding Player Account
The following PII will be collected and stored when you set up or initiate transactions to purchase Internet Tickets or a Lottery Subscription. It may also be shared with Third Party Service Providers for any legitimate business purposes, such as to process transactions or service your Players Account. The Website Providers and the Third Party Service Providers must comply with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards ("PCI DSS"). Please visit http://www.pcicomplianceguide.org/pcifaqs.php#4 for further information about the standards for a credit/debit card number.
iii.   Additional Information That May Be Collected
If you have a Player Account, information including, but not limited to the following, may also be collected from you:
1. transaction history (e.g., record of the games you played and numbers you played);
2. Precise geo-location data, if you access any Website from your mobile device and check the box to allow the Device Geo-Location Service to collect such information;
3. financial transaction history (e.g., record of the amount of money you spend on purchases, subscriptions, debits or credits to your Players Account, and your winnings);
4. gender;
5. preferred method of contact;
6. game play, promotional, and purchase location preferences; and
7. whether or not you wish to be included in marketing surveys.
iv.   Use of Your Information
By registering for and using a Players Account, you agree to allow the Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers to perform a Know Your Customer ("KYC") check to verify your name, age, date of birth, and/or any other information that you provide while visiting this Website. In addition, when you register for a Players Account, the Website Providers will verify that you are located in Illinois via geo-filtering of your IP address. If you opt-in to allow the Device Geo-location Service to collect information about the precise location of your device, the information collected will also be used to determine the appropriate marketing and promotional messages for you. To receive marketing, promotions and product updates on the Illinois Lottery via emails or push notifications, you MUST opt-in to receiving such communications from the Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers.
In addition, the Website Providers reserve the right, without limitation, to use Players Account information to enhance responsible gaming initiatives, as well as well as monitor the play of its internet lottery players.
The Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers may use your PII for various purposes including, but not limited to, the following
1. to administer the Illinois Lottery and your Players Account, including processing any Internet Tickets or Lottery Subscriptions that you purchase;
2. to verify your eligibility to play;
3. to contact you in response to your inquiries, comments, and suggestions;
4. to otherwise contact you, including to notify you if you win;
5. for the specific purpose for which it was volunteered;
6. to track your use of the Websites for internal market research;
7. to improve the Websites and the services we promote or provide through the Websites;
8. to customize the content and/or layout of the Websites for each visitor;
9. to ask for your participation in brief surveys;
10. to notify you about promotions, special offers, etc. regarding products and services provided by the Illinois Lottery or its agents; in connection with the legitimate business purposes of the Website Providers, Third Party Service Providers, or the Websites;
11. to generate aggregate statistical studies and to use the results of such aggregate statistical studies for marketing purposes and responsible gaming initiatives;
12. to protect and defend the rights or property of the Website Providers or the Third Party Service Providers;
13. to enforce this agreement, including the Illinois Lottery Terms and Conditions;
14. as required by law or regulation, or as requested by government or regulatory authorities, including but not limited to, gaming regulators and the Internal Revenue Service ("IRS"), or for the protection of persons or property;
15. in connection with an acquisition, merger, restructuring, sale, or other transfer involving all or any portion of the business associated with the Websites;
16. for online marketing purposes, which shall not include email unless you opt-in to receive marketing emails; and
17. any other business purposes, including those purposes described elsewhere in this Privacy Notice.
By submitting the foregoing information, you consent to its use for such purposes. When you sign up for a Players Account, the information you provide will be shared with the Third Party Service Providers that administer your account. Your Players Account is subject to separate Illinois Lottery Terms and Conditions located at https://www.illinoislottery.com/policy/privacy-policy. More information is available in the Illinois Lottery Terms and Conditions. Any questions regarding your account should be directed to the Player Hotline (1-800-252-1775).
NON-DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
In the event you decline to provide any PII, you limit the Illinois Lottery’s ability to serve you.
As noted above, no PII is collected about you during your visit to the Websites, unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an email, participating in a survey, registering for a Players Account, or using other interactive services that may be provided on the Websites. You may choose not to utilize some or all of these interactive services. While your choice not to participate in these activities may limit your ability to receive specific services or products through a Website, it will not prevent you from requesting services or products from the Illinois Lottery by other means and will not normally have an impact on your ability to take advantage of other (non-interactive) features of a Website, including browsing or downloading publicly available information. If you would like to participate in Illinois Lottery promotions and do not wish to enter PII through a Website, please contact the Illinois Lottery at (800) 252-1775.
REVIEW AND CORRECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
You can review any PII that is collected about you and request changes by using the Contact Us section at the end of this Privacy Notice. Reasonable steps will be taken to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. Corrections to your PII will be made instantly.
You can also review and correct certain PII in your Players Account profile, such as your name and contact information, by signing into your Players Account.
PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTION AND RELEASE AUTHORIZATION
To process your Players Account application, you authorize the Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers to collect the PII listed in Section III above. Without limiting the foregoing, if you win, you authorize the Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers to use and release certain PII, including, but not limited to, your name, hometown and any photograph, video or audio recording, in any medium (including but not limited to newspaper, television, radio, and internet), for purposes of marketing, advertising, or other purposes of the Illinois Lottery. If you do not provide all or any part of the PII requested, your application may not be processed. The Illinois Lottery requires certain PII to comply with the Internal Revenue Code and Tax Law income reporting and tax withholding requirements and under the authority of Internal Revenue Code and Tax Law Section 1604 to announce Illinois Lottery prize awards. The Illinois Lottery is the custodian of subscription and prize records and may be contacted by mail at: Illinois Lottery, P.O. Box 19081, Springfield, IL 62794-9081.
EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS
If you register for a Players Account or otherwise provide PII through a Website, you may receive email messages regarding Illinois Lottery products, such as games and promotions from the Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers (on behalf of the Illinois Lottery).
COMMUNICATIONS VIA EMAIL AND PUSH NOTIFICATION
To receive emails and push notifications about the Illinois Lottery's products such as games and promotions, you must opt-in to receive such messages by checking the box authorizing the Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers to send you such text messages.
USE OUTSIDE OF THE UNITED STATES
The Websites and material provided on the Websites are solely for the promotion of products, programs, and Illinois Lottery operations within the U.S. and specifically within the State of Illinois. Purchasers of Internet Tickets must be located within the geographical boundaries of the State of Illinois to make purchases. If you provide any PII to the Website Providers (including through the Contact Us section below), it may be transferred to and processed on computers in the U.S. and other countries. Do not provide your PII to the Website Providers, if you do not want it to be transferred to the United States or to other countries, or if the laws in the country from where you are attempting to access this Website restrict these types of transfers. Your submission of PII to the Website Providers will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Notice. Your submission of PII to the Website Providers through this Website means that you agree to the terms of this Privacy Notice.
WEBSITE FOR ADULT USE ONLY (AGE 18 AND OLDER)
The Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers will not knowingly collect PII from children or create profiles of children through the Websites. All registrants must be at least 18 years of age to participate in any and all Illinois Lottery transactions. All PII submitted to the Website Providers will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by State law, be subject to public access. The Illinois Lottery strongly encourages parents and teachers to be involved in children’s internet activities and to provide guidance whenever children are asked to provide PII via the internet.
DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED THOUGHT THIS WEBSITE
Your voluntary disclosure of PII to the Website Providers, whether solicited or unsolicited, constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of such information by the Website Providers and Third Party Service Providers for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice. If you provide PII on any Website, certain state or federal laws may protect that information. Once you provide PII, however, it becomes a public record that may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by state or federal laws.
Without limiting the foregoing, PII may be collected or disclosed without your consent, if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of the Illinois Lottery, or necessary for the Illinois Lottery to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation, including the Freedom of Information Act; (2) made pursuant to a court order, subpoena or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating your identity; (4) with affiliates of the Illinois Lottery, the Website Providers, or Third Party Service Providers to provide the services on the Websites; or (5) to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce the Illinois Lottery’s rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to the Illinois Lottery’s information technology assets or against other inappropriate use of the Websites.
In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and any state or federal laws, including the Freedom of Information Act, the state or federal laws will control.
DATA BREACH NOTIFICATION
In the event of a data breach, the Website Providers and/or the Third Party Service Providers will notify all Players Account holders of the breach in the most expedient time possible, without unreasonable delay. The disclosure notification may be via mail, email or other expedient methods such as a newspaper publication. Such notification shall include, but is not limited to (i) the toll free numbers and addresses for consumer reporting agencies, (ii) the toll-free number, address, and website address for the Federal Trade Commission, and (iii) a statement that the individual can obtain information from these sources about fraud alerts and security freezes. The notification, however, shall not include information concerning the number of individuals or entities affected by the breach.
CONTACT US
For questions regarding any Website, please contact: support@illinoislottery.com or 1-800-252-1775
Because the Websites do not encrypt incoming email, you should not send information that you consider sensitive through any Website.
